http://help.nfb.ca/important-notices/

Links to this Site
Sharing of NFB Content (embedding)
Kinds of information we collect
What are cookies and how does the NFB use them?
Ownership
All materials displayed or otherwise accessible through the Websites, including, without limitation, news articles, text, photographs, images, illustrations, audio clips, video clips, computer software and code (collectively the “Content”) are protected under Canadian and foreign copyright or other laws, and are owned by the NFB, its licensors or the party accredited as the provider of the Content. In addition, the Websites are protected under copyright law as a collective work and/or compilation pursuant to Canadian and foreign laws.
Over and above the access for a fee to the products of the online stores, governed by the Terms of sale of NFB products provided for below, the access to the Websites is authorized by the NFB to permit you to view, share and comment the Content for the purposes of a private and non-commercial use and as provided for and authorized by the normal features of the Websites and the following terms.
You shall respect all additional copyright notices, information and restrictions on or contained in any of the Content accessed through the Websites. Any use, reproduction, alteration, modification, public performance or display, uploading or posting onto the internet, transmission, redistribution or other exploitation of the Websites or of any Content, whether in whole or in part, other than expressly set out herein, is prohibited without the express written permission of the NFB.
Back to top
Trademarks
NATIONAL FILM BOARD OF CANADA, OFFICE NATIONAL DU FILM DU CANADA, NFB and ONF are official marks or trademarks of the NFB. Other names, words, titles, phrases, logos, designs, graphics, icons and trademarks displayed on the Websites may constitute registered or unregistered trademarks of the NFB or third parties. While certain trademarks of third parties may be used by the NFB under license, the display of third-party trademarks on the Websites should not be taken to imply any relationship or license between the NFB and the owner of said trademark or to imply that the NFB endorses the wares, services or business of the owner of said trademark. Nothing contained on the Websites should be construed as granting you any license or right to use any trademark logo or design of NFB or any third party, without the written permission of the NFB or the respective owner of any third-party trademark.
Back to top
Submissions
The Websites may provide features that allow you to post messages and content, to interact with the NFB and other users and to upload files, documents or other materials (collectively the “Submissions”). When using any of the features of the Websites which allow you to post, upload or make Submissions, it is a condition of your use of the Websites that you observe the rules of netiquette and that you do not: (i) restrict or inhibit any other user from using and enjoying the Websites, interfere or attempt to interfere with the proper workings of the site or do anything which in the sole discretion of the NFB imposes an unreasonable or disproportionately large load on the NFB website infrastructure; (ii) post or transmit any unlawful, threatening, abusive, libellous, defamatory, obscene, vulgar, pornographic, profane or indecent information of any kind, including, without limitation, any Submission constituting or encouraging conduct that would constitute a criminal offense, give rise to civil liability or otherwise violate any local, state, provincial, national or international law or regulation; (iii) post or transmit any submission, including, without limitation, articles, images, stories, software or other material, which violates or infringes upon the rights of others, including material which is an invasion of privacy or publicity rights or which is protected by any intellectual property rights, including, without limitation, copyright, patent, trade secret, trademark or other proprietary rights herein, or derivative works with respect thereto, without first obtaining permission from the owner or rights holder; (iv) post or transmit any Submission that promotes racism, bigotry, hatred or physical harm of any kind against any group or individual, could be harmful to minors, harasses or advocates harassment of another person, provides material that exploits people under the age of majority in a sexual or violent manner, provides instructional information about illegal activities, including, without limitation, the making or buying of illegal weapons; (v) post or submit any Submission which solicits passwords or personal identifying information for commercial or unlawful purposes from other users; (vi) post or transmit any Submission which contains a virus or other harmful component, or provides or creates computer viruses; (vii) post or transmit junk mail, chain letters, unsolicited mass mailing or spam; or (viii) use the Websites for commercial purposes, including, without limitation, posting, uploading or transmitting any Submissions which contain advertising or which engage in commercial activities and/or sales, or which involve contests, sweepstakes, barter, advertising, and/or pyramid schemes.
By posting or uploading Submissions to the Websites, you grant the NFB a royalty-free, perpetual, non-exclusive, irrevocable, unrestricted, worldwide license to: (i) use, reproduce, store, adapt, translate, modify, make derivative works from, transmit, distribute, publicly perform or display such Submissions for any purpose; and (ii) to sublicense to third parties the unrestricted right to exercise any of the foregoing rights. In addition to the grant of the above license, you hereby (i) agree to waive all moral rights in any Submission in favour of the NFB; (ii) consent to your name, address and e-mail appearing as the contributor of any submission, where applicable, and to the disclosure and/or display of such information and any other information which appears in or is associated with a submission; (iii) acknowledge and agree that the NFB is not responsible for any loss, damage, or corruption that may occur to your Submissions; and (iv) acknowledge and agree that any Submissions you provide for display on the Websites will be considered non-confidential.
The NFB may review Submissions before they are posted. The NFB may refuse to post any Submission to the Websites. The NFB reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to edit or remove any Submission, whether or not the Submission is in violation of the provisions hereof or otherwise objectionable. You acknowledge and agree that the NFB may, in its sole discretion, monitor the Websites periodically and disclose any information as necessary to satisfy any law, regulation or other governmental or court request, to operate the Websites properly or to protect itself or other users of the Websites. Any such disclosure shall be in accordance with the NFB’s Privacy Policy.
The NFB is not responsible for the Content of any Submission. Submissions represent the views and opinions of the person(s) posting the Submission and do not represent the views or opinions of the NFB.
While the NFB is under no obligation to investigate any complaint regarding any submission, it may, in its sole discretion, investigate complaints and take any actions it deems appropriate in the circumstances, including, without limitation, removing the offending communication from the Websites and terminating the submitting party’s right to access and use the Websites (or any portion thereof).
Back to top
Software licenses and ownership
All software embedded in or located on or at the Websites, including, without limitation, all computer code of all types, including all files and/or images contained in or generated by such software (software) is protected by copyright and may be protected by other rights. All such software is owned by the NFB, its licensors or the party accredited with ownership of such software. You are hereby granted the right to access and use the software embedded and integrated into the Websites, subject to (i) the terms and conditions of this agreement, and (ii) any additional conditions which may be imposed on your access and use of such software.
If the Websites provide software for download, unless otherwise provided, you are hereby granted, subject (i) to the terms of this agreement and (ii) to any other terms and conditions that may apply to your downloading and use of such software, a personal, non-transferable, non-exclusive license to (i) install and run one copy of the software in object-code format on a non-networked computer for your personal, non-commercial use; and (ii) to reproduce the software only as reasonably required to install, run and make reasonable backup copies as allowed by law.
Except to the extent expressly permitted in this agreement, you may not: (i) use, reproduce, modify, adapt, translate, upload, download or transmit the software in whole or in part; (ii) sell, rent, lease, licence, transfer or otherwise provide access to the software; (iii) alter, remove or cover any trademarks or proprietary notices included in the software; and/or (iv) decompile, disassemble, decrypt, extract or reverse engineer the software or assist others in doing so.
Nothing contained in the Websites shall be construed as granting you any right, title, interest or other license in or to any software embedded or integrated into the Websites or made available for download from the Websites, including, but not limited, to any intellectual property rights in the software.
All software embedded or integrated into the Websites is provided as is, without warranties of any kind, either expressed or implied, including, without limitation, any warranty (i) that the software is of merchantable quality or is fit for any particular purpose; (ii) that the software will conform with any specification(s) relating to the software; (iii) that the software will be free from material defects; (iv) that the software contains no computer viruses or other contaminants; or (v) that the software shall process date-related and time-related data without causing any processing interruptions, abnormal termination or process or manipulate any time-related data.
Back to top
Third-party Materials
Some of the materials and graphical elements found on the Websites are subject to copyrights held by other organizations. In such cases, some restrictions on the reproduction of materials or graphical elements may apply and it may be necessary to seek permission from the rights holder prior to reproducing the material.
To obtain information concerning copyright ownership and restrictions on reproduction on this site, please
contact us.
Back to top
Hyperlinking Notice
The Websites contain links to third party sites. The NFB provides these links only as a service and convenience to our visitors. We take no responsibility for the content at third party sites including, without limitation, any representation or warranty regarding the legality, accuracy, reliability, completeness, timeliness, suitability of any content on any third-party website. The link to them in no way implies an endorsement or recommendation of the products, services or information found there.
A third party site may have a privacy policy different from that of the NFB and may provide less security than the Websites. The NFB disclaims all liability with regard to your access to linked sites. When you link to sites external to the Websites, you do so at your own risk.
The NFB reserves the right to regularly review and re-evaluate any and all links and reserves the right to terminate any link without prior notification.
Requests for hosting links to third party sites should be directed to webmaster@nfb.ca.
Back to top
Links to this Site
You may create links to our Site for non-commercial purposes only. These links should not be interpreted as a validation or endorsement or promotion of third-party content. If you wish to solicit a business relationship with the National Film Board of Canada, you need an explicit written agreement.
While the NFB encourages links to the Websites, it does not wish to be linked to or from any third-party website which (i) contains, posts or transmits any unlawful, threatening, abusive, libellous, defamatory, obscene, vulgar, pornographic, profane or indecent information of any kind, including, without limitation, any content constituting or encouraging conduct that would constitute a criminal offense, give rise to civil liability or otherwise violate any local, state, provincial, national or international law, regulation which may be damaging or detrimental to the activities, operations, credibility or integrity of the NFB or which contains, posts or transmits any material or information of any kind which promotes racism, bigotry, hatred or physical harm of any kind against any group or individual, could be harmful to minors, harasses or advocates harassment of another person, provides material that exploits people under the age of 18 in a sexual or violent manner, provides instructional information about illegal activities, including, without limitation, the making or buying of illegal weapons; or (ii) contains, posts or transmits any information, software or other material which violates or infringes upon the rights of others, including material which is an invasion of privacy or publicity rights, or which is protected by copyright, trademark or other proprietary rights. The NFB reserves the right to prohibit or refuse to accept any link to the Websites, including, without limitation, any link which contains or makes available any content or information of the foregoing nature, at any time. You agree to remove any link you may have to the Websites upon the request of the NFB.
Back to top
Sharing of NFB Content (embedding)
By using the embed code to display on third party sites (Third Party Sites) the NFB video Content located on the NFB Websites which are accompanied by an embed code (the “Embeddable Content”) you agree to be bound by the following terms:
Subject to the general conditions of use of the Websites, the NFB grants you a non-exclusive, non-transferable license to use the embeddable computer code to display on Third Party Sites the Embeddable Content. You may not copy, re-publish, edit, alter, add to or use the Embeddable Content, embed code or embeddable player in any other way.
All title, ownership rights and intellectual property rights in and to the Embeddable Content, and any code made available by the NFB to embed the Embeddable Content and the embeddable player shall remain the property of the NFB and/or its licensors.
You may not use the Embeddable Content on any websites that contain content described in the Links to this Site section.
The Embeddable Content is for your personal use only and cannot be used in any commercial way. You may not charge visitors any fee for accessing the Embeddable Content, use the Embeddable Content as means to secure advertising, or commercialize the Embeddable Content or embeddable player in any other way.
You must create a link back to the NFB Websites on the pages of the Third Party Sites where the Embeddable Content is displayed.
You may not directly or indirectly suggest any endorsement or approval by the NFB of the Third Party Sites displaying the Embeddable Content or any non-NFB entity, product or content or any views expressed within Third Party Sites without the NFB’s prior written approval.
You may not use the Embeddable Content in any way that could bring the NFB into disrepute or otherwise cause any loss or damage to the NFB.
You acknowledge that the NFB has sole editorial control over the Embeddable Content at all times and it may change or restrict, suspend or terminate any or all Embeddable Content or your access to the Embeddable Content at any time at its sole discretion without liability.
You acknowledge that the Embeddable Content is made available by the NFB on an “as is” and “as available” basis and the NFB gives no warranty of any kind in relation to the Embeddable Content, embed code or the embeddable player.
Back to top
Sharing of Campus Playlist
The sharing of a CAMPUS playlist and films contained therein is intended for educational purposes only (including lesson preparation, homework and classroom assignments). A playlist and the films contained therein may not be shared on any third party sites, including any social media platform, or beyond the intended educational audience enrolled in or attending classes taught by the owner of the associated CAMPUS profile. Such profile owner shall use reasonable means to control the sharing of their playlist and failure to adhere to these terms of use can result in revocation of CAMPUS privileges.
Back to top
Official Languages Notice
The Websites respect the Official Languages Act and the NFB is committed to ensuring all information on them is available in both French and English. However, users should be aware that some information from external sources is available as a courtesy and will only be available in the language in which it was provided. Some hyperlinks direct users to sites of organizations or other entities that are not subject to the Official Languages Act.
Back to top
Accessibility Notice
The NFB is committed to equitable access to information, regardless of the technologies used. We are continually striving to make our site accessible to all, including persons with disabilities and to those who use assistive devices.
The Websites are developed according to the Common Look and Feel Standards for the internet, including the Accessibility Standards which require compliance with the
World Wide Web Consortium’s (W3C) Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI) Guidelines Version 1.0 – Priority 1 and 2 Checkpoints
.
Back to top
Subscribing, registering and opening an account
By completing your registration application, you declare that you are authorized to open an account, that you understand these terms and conditions and that you agree to be bound by them.
To open an account or to subscribe to the Websites, you must provide true, accurate, current and complete information. If the NFB has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, the NFB has the right to suspend or terminate your access to and use of the Websites.
You must then choose a password. You assume full responsibility for protecting the confidentiality of your customer account and your password. You also assume full responsibility for all transactions carried out using your account or password.
You agree to notify the NFB immediately of any unauthorized use of your account or password.
The NFB’s use of any personally identifying information you provide as part of the registration process is governed by the terms of the NFB’s Privacy Policy.
If you are an institutional customer, you declare that any person who uses your account and your password is a person authorized to place orders for our products.
The NFB cannot and will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from the NFB’s failure or your failure to protect your password or account information.
Back to top
Disclaimer of warranties
The Websites and all Content are provided as is. By accessing and using the Websites you acknowledge and agree that use of the Websites and the Content is entirely at your own risk. The NFB makes no representations or warranties regarding the Websites and the Content, including, without limitation, no representation or warranty that:
the Websites and/or Content will be accurate, complete, reliable, suitable or timely;
any Content, including, without limitation, any information, data, software, product or service contained in or made available through the Websites will be of merchantable quality or fit for a particular purpose;
the operation of the Websites will be uninterrupted or error free;
defects or errors in the Websites will be corrected;
the Websites will be free from viruses or harmful components; and that
communications to or from the Websites will be secure or not intercepted.
Back to top
Limitation of liability
Subject to applicable law, in no event shall the NFB, its officers, directors, employees, agents, licensors or their respective successors and assigns, be liable for any special, indirect, incidental or consequential damages of any kind, including, without limitation, any loss or damages in the nature of or relating to lost business, lost savings, lost data and/or lost profits, regardless of the cause and whether arising in contract (including fundamental breach), tort (including negligence) or otherwise. The foregoing limitation shall apply even if the NFB knew of or ought to have known of the possibility of such damages.
In no event shall the NFB, its officers, directors, employees, agents, licensors or their respective successors and assigns, be liable for damages under this agreement, whether arising in contract (including fundamental breach), tort (including negligence) or otherwise even if the NFB has been advised or ought to have known of the possibility of such damages.
The NFB expressly disclaims any and all liability for the acts, omissions or conduct of any third-party user of the Websites or any advertiser or sponsor of the website (collectively, third-party user). Under no circumstances shall the NFB and its officers, directors, employees, agents licensors, be liable for any injury, loss, damage (including special, indirect, incidental or consequential damages) or expense arising in any manner whatsoever from (i) the acts, omissions or conduct of any third-party user; and (ii) any use or inability to use any materials, software, content, goods or services located at or made available at any website linked to or from the Websites.
If you decide to access or use any linked website or content, materials, software, goods or services from a website linked to the Websites, you do so entirely at your own risk.
Back to top
Indemnity
You agree to indemnify, defend and hold harmless the NFB and its officers, directors, employees, agents, licensors and their respective successors and assigns, from and against any and all claims, demands, liabilities, costs or expenses whatsoever, including, without limitation, legal fees and disbursements resulting directly or indirectly from: (i) your breach of any of the terms and conditions of this Agreement; (ii) your access, use or inability to access or use the Websites or any website to which the Websites are or may be linked to from time to time; (iii) your use of, reliance on, publication, communication or distribution, uploading or downloading of anything on or from the Websites; and/or (iv) your violation of any law or regulation.
Back to top
Governing legislation
The NFB is an agent of the federal Crown, which operates the Websites from its offices located within the Province of Quebec, Canada. The Websites are designed to comply with the laws that apply in Canada. By accessing or using the Websites, you agree that all matters relating to your access to, or use of, the Websites and/or the Content shall be governed by the laws of the Province of Quebec and the laws of Canada, without regard to the conflict of laws principles thereof. You agree and hereby submit to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the Federal Court of Canada and/or the courts of the Province of Quebec with respect to such matters.
Back to top
NFB Campus – Streaming Subscriptions – Terms of Use
Together with the general terms of use of the NFB.ca and ONF.ca websites, the following Terms of Use govern your use of the NFB Campus streaming website (the “Website”).
Grant of Rights
Pursuant to an agreement between you and the NFB for a subscription to the Website, the NFB grants to you (and, in the case of group subscriptions, your authorized users as described in a subscription agreement) for the applicable term a limited, non-exclusive, terminable, non-transferable license to access the Website and any and all content included therein such as audio-visual works, still images, text, study guides, indexes, databases, etc. (the “Content”).
Back to top
Use for Educational, Non-Commercial Purposes Only
You (and your authorized users, in the case of group subscriptions) may use the Website and the Content for bona fide educational and research purposes only, and may not use them in any commercial or for-profit manner. You may access the Website and the Content outside of a school facility solely for bona fide educational and research purposes.
Individual teachers can present the Website and the Content to groups of students within a classroom setting of 150 students or less provided no entry fee is charged.
NFB reserves the right to limit your and/or any users’ use of the Website in the event that NFB, in its sole and absolute discretion, deems your and/or any users’ use thereof to be inconsistent with educational and research purposes, and/or inconsistent with these Terms of Use.
You may access and create playlists as permitted by the Website’s features. You may also select and save individual video segments (chaptering) to add to a playlist solely in connection with classroom or other related projects.
Back to top
Limitations on use
You may not download (other than through page caching necessary for your use, or as otherwise expressly permitted by these Terms of Use or Content designated on the Website as downloadable), modify, copy, distribute, transmit, display, perform, reproduce, duplicate, publish, license, create derivative works from, or offer for sale any information contained on, or obtained from or through, the Website, without the NFB’s express written permission. You may not circumvent, remove, alter, deactivate, degrade or thwart any of the Content protections in the Website. You may not frame or utilize any framing techniques to enclose any trademark, logo, or other proprietary information (including images, text, page layout, or form) of the NFB without our express written permission. You may not purchase search terms or use any meta tags or any other “hidden text” utilizing the NFB name or trademarks without our express written permission.
Download-to-Own (DTO) content is licensed for private home use only.
Back to top
Availability
The availability of the Content will change from time to time. The quality of the display of the streaming Content may vary from computer to computer, and device to device, and may be affected by a variety of factors, such as your location, the bandwidth available through and/or speed of your Internet connection. You are responsible for all Internet access charges. Please check with your Internet provider for information on possible Internet data usage charges. The NFB makes no representations or warranties about the quality of your instant watching experience on your display.
Back to top
Group Subscriptions for Organizations
Organizations (such as schools, school boards, etc.) who wish to purchase group subscriptions for multiple users may do so. For more information please contact an NFB Sales Agent.
Back to top
Security and Use of Passwords
Each user shall have a valid username and password for the purpose of accessing the Website and the Content (the “Log-In Information”). You (and, in the case of group subscriptions, your authorized users) must keep all Log-In Information strictly confidential, and all Log-In Information may be used only by the assigned user. You and your users are responsible for maintaining the security and confidentiality of all Log-In Information, and for preventing access to the Website and/or the Content by unauthorized persons using a user’s Log-In Information. Unauthorized access to or use of the Website and/or the Content by someone using a user’s Log-In information may be attributed to such user.
Back to top
30 Day Money Back Guarantee
If you are not completely satisfied, you may cancel the subscription agreement within 30 days of your initial subscription.
A request for the 30-Day Money Back Guarantee must be submitted to sales@nfb.ca and include the following information: email address or username being use to access the service and reason for requesting refund (i.e., issues with the features provided, content offered, technical difficulties or any other reason). A refund will be processed within approximately 2 business days following reception of the Customer’s request.
After 30 days following the initial subscription, refunds are available only in the instance of an individual subscription being superseded by an organizational group subscription (“I purchased a Teacher subscription, but now my school/board has also subscribed me: what happens to my individual subscription?”); NFB will refund the remaining months on the individual agreement (excluding current month).
Back to top
Communications from NFB
The NFB may periodically contact users for customer service purposes, including product information (such as product updates and Content updates), as well as to ascertain subscriber/user satisfaction and preferences via surveys and questionnaires. By accessing the Website and the Content, users consent to receive such communications.
You agree that NFB may reference its business relationship with you in its marketing or sales materials.
Back to top
Changes to Terms of Use
NFB reserves the right to change these Terms of Use from time to time. Such changes will become effective when the NFB posts the revised Terms of Use on the Website. Users should check the Terms of Use from time to time, as they are bound by the Terms of Use posted on the Website at the time of access. Any revised Terms of Use shall supercede all previous versions.
Back to top
No Warranties, Limitation of Liability
The Website and the Content are provided as is. The NFB may, in its sole discretion, make changes to the Website and/or the Content, including but not limited to modifying, adding and/or removing films or other Content.
Back to top
Termination
In the event that you breach any term of the subscriber agreement, or you and/or any of your authorized users breach these Terms of Use, the NFB may terminate the subscriber agreement in whole or in part immediately upon written notice to you. Upon expiration of the Term of the subscription agreement or prior termination, all access to and use of the Website and the Content must cease.
Back to top
Terms of sale of NFB products
The following Terms of sale of NFB products (the “Terms of sale”) govern the relations between the NFB and any user who purchases products from the Websites.
The Terms of sale govern the transactions made from the Websites related to products offered for sale via download (the “Download”) and on a physical medium (DVD and Blu-ray), as well as the sales of other products offered online by the NFB.
Since the services offered on the Websites are likely to evolve, the Terms of sale are subject to modifications. Thus, you are invited to consult them before using the services of the Websites.
The applicable Terms of sale are those that are accessible on the Websites at the time of connection to the Websites or at the time of the effective order.
Online Stores
“Online DVD Consumer” Store: the DVD and Blu-ray products of this store are offered only to the general public domiciled in Canada and/or the United States, and are available solely for private viewing.
“Download Consumer” Store: the products of this store are offered via download only to the general public solely for private viewing.
“Learning Resources” Store: these products are offered only to educational institutions, government agencies, businesses, band councils, social service agencies, and professional, religious or cultural organizations or libraries for performance to the public free of charge.
Back to top
Online commerce conditions
The Websites may allow you to purchase many different types of products and services online that are provided by the NFB (the “Wares and Services”). When ordering Wares and Services on the Websites, you must provide complete and accurate personal information consisting of your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card information and shipping address, as well as any other information requested.
Your receipt of an electronic form or other form of order confirmation does not signify our acceptance of your order, nor does it constitute confirmation of our offer to sell. Your submission of an order to us shall be deemed to constitute an offer to purchase, which shall remain open for a reasonable time, unless we agree otherwise, and will be deemed to be accepted by us only upon shipment of the Wares and Services. The NFB, in its sole discretion, reserves the right at any time after receipt of your order, to accept or decline your order for any reason, especially if the Wares and Services are listed at an incorrect price, due to a typographical error or an error in pricing information.
You acknowledge and agree that the price of the Wares and Services is subject to change without notice and that the Wares and Services are subject to availability. The sale of the Wares and Services is void where prohibited by law. The NFB also reserves the right to cancel or refuse an order in the case of non-payment of a previous order or if it turns out that you have not respected the Terms of use and sale or the laws in force, in particular those related to copyright.
The Websites may allow you to purchase many different types of products and services online that are provided by third parties (the Third-Party Merchandise). The NFB is not responsible for the legality, quality, accuracy, timeliness, reliability or any other aspect of any Third-Party Merchandise. If you make a purchase from a third-party web hosted by the website or linked from the website, the information obtained during your visit to any third-party website and the information that you give, such as your credit card number and contact information, is collected by the third-party website and not by the NFB.
You release the NFB and its officers, directors, employees, agents and their respective successors and assigns from any damages that you incur, and agree not to assert any claims against them, arising from your purchase or use of the Wares and Services or Third-Party Merchandise made available on the Websites or by third-party Websites through the Websites.
Your use of the Websites allows to conclude contracts and to make online transactions. You acknowledge that your electronic validations mean your acceptance and express your intention to be bound and to pay for your purchases. Your acceptance and intention to be bound by those electronic validations apply to all transactions made on the Websites, including cancelation requests, policies, contracts and registrations. To access your Downloads and store them, you may need certain equipment and software for which you are solely responsible.
After filling out the forms, you carry out your selected order by following the instructions displayed on the screen. At the end of the ordering procedure and before the final conclusion of the contract, a recap of your order is displayed on the screen for confirmation. In light of this recap, you may identify errors made in the entry of data and correct them, as well as confirm or cancel your order. The contract is final once you confirm the recap of your order.
The NFB will immediately send you an electronic confirmation of the details of your order. The transfer of ownership of the ordered products is subject to full payment of the price. The payment shall be considered complete upon effective receipt of the price by the NFB.
Back to top
Intellectual property rights
Whether you are a customer of the Online DVD Store, the Download Consumer Stores or Learning Resources Store, you agree to comply with all copyright, trade-mark or intellectual property notices appearing on our products. In particular:
Any form of reproduction, in whole or in part, by any method now known or not yet known, is strictly prohibited without prior written authorization from the NFB;
You may not rent, sell, alter or redistribute our products, in whole or in part, or use them in any other way for financial or commercial gain.
If you are a customer of the Online DVD or Download Consumer Stores, you may use our products for private purposes only. You may not use them for any other purpose, especially for commercial and educational purposes and public performances and retransmissions. You may copy, store and engrave the products of the Download Consumer Store in a way that is reasonably necessary for personal and non-commercial use.
If you are a professional purchaser and you wish to use any of our products on a network, you must contact our Sales and Customer Service to obtain prior written authorization from the NFB.
See our Contact Us section for detailed contact information.
Back to top
Availability of products
The NFB does not guarantee that all films offered for sale are available in both English and French versions. The NFB offers its products only in the versions that are available and that already exist.
Due to certain restrictions, the NFB does not guarantee that the catalogues of products offered in all stores are identical.
Films from the Online DVD Consumer and Learning Resources Stores are available in NTSC DVD format (for North America). Other formats are available on demand.
Back to top
Territory of sale
The NFB offers its products for direct on-line sale only within Canada and the United States.
Back to top
Prices
The prices to be paid are the prices shown for the products and vary by category of customer (DVD Consumer, Download Consumer or Learning Resources).
The applicable sales taxes are not included in the prices shown. Shipping and delivery charges (for products on a physical medium) and the sales taxes are additional.
Delivery Method
Ship Time
Total Shipping Price
Regular parcel
(Canada Post)
3-6 business days after order is shipped
(urban centres)
First item: $4.00
Each additional item: $0.75,
up to a maximum: $50.00
XpressPost
2-3 business days after order is shipped
(urban centres)
First item: $13.00
Each additional item: $1.25,
up to a maximum: $100.00
All prices shown are in Canadian dollars in the Canadian stores and in U.S. dollars in the United States stores.
The prices for products offered on these Websites may be different from prices offered at other authorized points of sale.
The NFB reserves the right to change the prices of the products offered on these Websites at any time and without notice.
Back to top
Paying for your orders
Online DVD and Download Consumer Stores orders: We accept VISA, MasterCard and American Express. If you wish to place your order by telephone, or to send us your personal credit card information by fax and then complete the order by telephone, you may do so by contacting Sales and Customer Service.
Learning Resources Store orders: These orders must be paid for by VISA, MasterCard or American Express. Customers who already have a pre-approved account may pay their accounts by purchase order. For more information regarding this option, please contact Sales and Customer Service.
Back to top
Product deliveries
For Online DVD Consumer and Learning Resources orders, the NFB will deliver products to the address in Canada or the United States that you indicate when you place the order. Delivery time for items in inventory is about one week, or two to three weeks for articles that are not available in inventory. The Canada Post delivery times mentioned above are in addition to these estimates. If you need more information about the delivery of your order, please contact Sales and Customer Service.
Back to top
Satisfaction Guarantee
Our guarantee is simple. If you are not completely satisfied with the quality of the product you have purchased, we will offer you a full reimbursement in the case of a Download or, in the case of a DVD, a reimbursement, exchange or credit within 30 days of the date of delivery.
Before returning a product, however, please contact Sales and Customer Service to obtain a Return Materials Authorization (RMA), which must appear on your return. Some restrictions may apply. Please include a copy of the packing slip with your return. Products on a physical medium (DVD) should be returned to this address:
National Film Board of Canada
ATTN: RECEPTION, A-8
3155 CÔTE DE LIESSE
MONTREAL QC
H4N 2N4
Back to top
General
Force majeure
In the event of circumstances beyond our control or force majeure, the NFB will not be liable for failure to perform any of its obligations to you, in whole or in part, or for any damage or loss you may suffer.
Back to top
Modifications to conditions of use
The NFB reserves the right to modify the content of these Terms of use and sale at any time and it is your responsibility to consult the Terms of use and sale on a regular basis to determine whether any modifications have been made. By using these Websites, you agree to the rules and conditions. Use of the Websites after such changes are posted will signify your agreement to these revised terms.
Back to top
Other
Any consent by the NFB to, or waiver of, a breach of this Agreement which you have committed, whether express or implied, shall not constitute a consent to, or waiver of, any other, different or subsequent breach. You may not assign or transfer this Agreement or any right or obligation hereunder. If any term or provision of this Agreement is held by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, it shall be severed and the remaining provisions shall remain in full force without being invalidated in any way. This Agreement is not intended to create a partnership, joint venture, or agency relationship between the parties. Except for any agreements with the NFB that expressly reference this Agreement, this is the entire agreement between you and the NFB relating to the matters contained herein.
If you have questions or comments, please contact us.
Back to top
Privacy Policy
The National Film Board of Canada gives the utmost importance to the privacy of visitors to our Websites. We diligently follow Canadian government policies with regards to privacy. We stay abreast of the latest technologies and best practices in the industry to provide you with a reliable and safe Internet experience.
When you enter the Web sites, you are anonymous and will remain that way unless you choose otherwise. Please read the following text explaining the rules governing your visit. If you are under the age of majority in your province of domicile, please show this section to your parents or legal guardians.
Principles
Kinds of information we collect
What are cookies and how does the NFB use them?
Disclosure of information to third parties
Links to other sites
Security
How to access, edit or delete your personal information
Revisions to the Privacy Policy
Who to contact about this Privacy Policy
Back to top
Principles
The NFB is an agent of the federal Crown and complies with the Canadian Privacy Act (R.S. 1985 c. P-21), which protects personal information from improper use and disclosure and gives individuals the right to request access to information about themselves, to request correction of their personal information if they feel it contains errors or omissions, or to have their personal information removed from personal information banks.
Back to top
Kinds of information we collect
There are two kinds of information that Websites can obtain about you: aggregate information and personal information.
Back to top
Aggregate information
Aggregate information is anonymous data that Websites use to help improve the quality of the Web pages and to administer the Site.
We at nfb.ca and onf.ca collect certain aggregate information such as your IP address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you enter our site), browser type (e.g. Firefox or Internet Explorer) and domain name (e.g. xyz.com). We do this in the background so it does not affect your navigation speed. None of this information is connected with personal information about you. The NFB performs statistical analyses of user behaviour in order to measure interest in and use of the various sections of its Site (e.g. number of visitors per page, length of time spent on page) so as to improve design and navigation and to help diagnose problems. Only aggregate data is used for this purpose.
Back to top
Personal information
Personal information is any information that personally identifies you. It could be your first and last name, your e-mail address, your home address, your telephone number, your credit card number, information contained in a résumé, or your personal views and opinions.
Such personal information is needed when, for instance, you order products online, post a comment, engage with an interactive experience, or electronically apply for a job at the NFB, or if we need to reply to you.
When you order products online and supply a credit card number, this number is encrypted and transmitted to the Canadian government payment gateway (Receiver General Buy Button) for the electronic acceptance of payments. Credit card numbers are used only for processing payments and are not retained for any other purpose. The payment process uses a Secure Socket Layer (SSL). Once the customer’s personal information has been provided securely, the credit card number is immediately encrypted by buy button in secure transaction storage and no longer retrievable in an unencrypted format.
We may also occasionally ask you to voluntarily provide us with other demographic information or information about your interest in and use of various products. This enables us to give you more appropriate information or more personalized service.
We will always inform you when personal information is required in order to obtain a service. If we are asking for mandatory information, we will mark it with an asterisk (*). If there is no asterisk, you need not provide the information.
Back to top
What are cookies and how does the NFB use them?
“Cookies” are small text files that are saved on your computer’s hard drive when you access certain Websites or certain parts of Websites. By means of cookies, a website can recognize repeat users, facilitate the user’s access to and use of the site and allow a site to track usage behaviour so as to improve Content.
The NFB uses cookies to recognize you when you return to our Websites and let you save your password for password-protected areas and use a shopping cart. We will not use cookies to track non-NFB usage.
If you do not want a cookie placed on your computer by the NFB, it is your responsibility to set your browser to disable cookies. However, this may result in your being unable to access some aspects of the NFB site. Refer to your Internet browser’s manual to learn how to complete this task.
If you are willing to accept cookies but wish to be informed first, you can set your browser to give you a warning prompt. Refer to your Internet browser’s manual to learn how to complete this task.
Back to top
Disclosure of information to third parties
Personal information provided to the NFB is never sold or rented. We will disclose information we maintain only if so required by a subpoena, warrant or court order. Otherwise, personal information provided to the NFB will never be passed on to third parties without the prior knowledge and consent of the person concerned.
If we ever need to share personal information with a third party (e.g. if we ask a consultant to conduct a survey for us), we will always let you know that the information will be shared and what it will be used for. It will then be up to you to decide whether to provide the information or not.
As a government institution subject to the Canadian Privacy Act (R.S. 1985 c. P-21), we must notify the Privacy Commissioner in writing of any disclosure of personal information before using that information for a purpose other than that for which it was obtained.
Back to top
Links to other sites
Our website may contain links to suitable third-party Websites. However, the linked sites are not under the control of the NFB, and we are not responsible for the content of any linked site or any link contained in a linked site.
Back to top
Security
At nfb.ca and onf.ca, whenever you send us personal information, we immediately make every effort to ensure its security on our systems. Any personal information you give us is kept in secure files. Access is limited to authorized employees on a need-to-know basis.
With regard to the information required for an online transaction, the existing credit card services contract for the federal government requires the payment service provider to provide levels of data and processing security and integrity that are standard within the banking industry.
But remember, you must also protect yourself against the unauthorized use of your credit card, nfb.ca ID and password. Please keep in mind that your ID and password are the link to your account with us and the personal information it contains. Please take care when using and storing them. The NFB recommends that you not divulge your password to anyone.
Back to top
How to access, edit or delete your personal information
If you wish to access personal information collected about you, inform us of changes to personal information previously provided, or even remove your personal information from our database, please send an e-mail to ATIP-AIPRP@nfb.ca. The person in charge of answering your request in regard to the Privacy Policy is:
ATIP Coordinator (Access to Information and Privacy)
National Film Board of Canada
1501 Bleury,
H3A 2J2,
Montreal, QC, Canada,
514-294-5621
Back to top
Revisions to the Privacy Policy
By using these Websites, you are agreeing to the terms and conditions of the NFB Privacy Policy. As our Site is constantly evolving, we reserve the right to modify this policy at any time without prior notice. This Privacy Policy serves as an expression of our commitment to protecting personal information. We invite you to consult it regularly.
Back to top
Who to contact about this Privacy Policy
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us online or by phone:
http://help.nfb.ca/contact-the-nfb/
If you are not satisfied with the response you receive from the NFB, you may contact the Office of the Privacy Commissioner at the following numbers:
Toll-free: 1-800-282-1376
Phone: (819) 994-5444
TTY: (819) 994-6591
Back to top
